You hear the sudden, cheerful
You
hear
the
sudden,
cheerful
pops from a pot of
pops
from
a
pot
of
popcorn kernels as they heat.
popcorn
kernels
as
they
heat.
This isn't just corn expanding,
This
isn't
just
corn
expanding,
it's a miniature pressure cooker
it's
a
miniature
pressure
cooker
explosion. Inside each hard kernel
explosion.
Inside
each
hard
kernel
is a small amount of
is
a
small
amount
of
water stored in a soft,
water
stored
in
a
soft,
starchy center.
starchy
center.
As the kernel heats, this
As
the
kernel
heats,
this
water turns to steam,
water
turns
to
steam,
building immense pressure. The hard
building
immense
pressure.
The
hard
outer shell, called the pericarp,
outer
shell,
called
the
pericarp,
is strong enough to contain
is
strong
enough
to
contain
it, until the temperature reaches
it,
until
the
temperature
reaches
around 180 degrees Celsius. Then,
around
degrees
Celsius.
Then,
the pressure becomes too great.
the
pressure
becomes
too
great.
The shell
ruptures catastrophically, and
The
shell
ruptures
catastrophically,
and
the superheated starch and steam
the
superheated
starch
and
steam
inside instantly expand,
inside
instantly
expand,
turning the kernel inside out
turning
the
kernel
inside
out
into a fluffy white puff.
into
a
fluffy
white
puff.
Each pop is the sound
Each
pop
is
the
sound
of a tiny hole failing,
of
a
tiny
hole
failing,
releasing its stored steam and
releasing
its
stored
steam
and
starch in a delicious burst.
starch
in
a
delicious
burst.